Audit Report: Flask To-Do List Application
Executive Summary
This audit report outlines the findings of a security audit conducted on the Flask To-Do List application. The audit aimed to identify potential security vulnerabilities and provide recommendations for improving the application's security posture.

Audit Findings
1. *Input Validation Issue*: The application doesn't properly validate user input, making it vulnerable to SQL injection attacks. Specifically, the `todo_item` parameter in the `/add` route is not sanitized, allowing an attacker to inject malicious SQL code.
2. *Authentication Weakness*: The application uses weak password hashing, making it vulnerable to password cracking attacks. The `werkzeug.security.generate_password_hash` function is used, but it's not configured to use a sufficient work factor.
3. *Data Storage Vulnerability*: The application stores sensitive data in plaintext, making it vulnerable to data breaches. Specifically, the `todo_item` data is stored in the SQLite database without any encryption.

Recommendations
1. *Input Validation*: Implement proper input validation and sanitization for all user input. Use libraries like `wtforms` to validate and sanitize form data.
2. *Password Hashing*: Use a stronger password hashing algorithm like `bcrypt` or `argon2`. Configure the work factor to a sufficient value to slow down the hashing process.
3. *Data Encryption*: Implement encryption for sensitive data stored in the database. Use libraries like `cryptography` to encrypt and decrypt data.

Code Examples
1. *Input Validation*:
from wtforms import Form, StringField, validators

class TodoForm(Form):
    todo_item = StringField('Todo Item', [validators.Length(min=1, max=255)])

@app.route('/add', methods=['POST'])
def add_todo():
    form = TodoForm(request.form)
    if form.validate():
        # Add todo item to database
        pass
    else:
        # Handle validation errors
        pass
2. *Password Hashing*:
from flask_bcrypt import Bcrypt

bcrypt = Bcrypt(app)

@app.route('/register', methods=['POST'])
def register():
    password = request.form['password']
    hashed_password = bcrypt.generate_password_hash(password).decode('utf-8')
    # Store hashed password in database
    pass
3. *Data Encryption*:
from cryptography.fernet import Fernet

key = Fernet.generate_key()
cipher_suite = Fernet(key)

@app.route('/add', methods=['POST'])
def add_todo():
    todo_item = request.form['todo_item']
    encrypted_todo_item = cipher_suite.encrypt(todo_item.encode('utf-8'))
    # Store encrypted todo item in database
    pass
Conclusion
The Flask To-Do List application has several security vulnerabilities that need to be addressed. By implementing proper input validation, stronger password hashing, and data encryption, the application's security posture can be significantly improved. We recommend working with the development team to remediate the identified security vulnerabilities and perform follow-up testing to enŷtsure the vulnerabilities have been properly addressed.